<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-daylight-saving</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1918-03-30/ed-1/?sp=3&q=daylight+saving</id>
	      <rel>1</rel>
	      <text>
        Clocks to Be Turned Ahead at
2 A. M. To-Morrow With
Elaborate Ceremony.
The programme is complets to-dsy
for welcoming Amerlcs's first twenty-three.
hour day with due dignity
and ceremony. New York, which
originated tha daylight aavlng move
ment. will lead in the celebration.
All clocks are to be puahed ahead
one hour to-morrow morning. Tke
hour from 2 lo J will he dropped, cut
out as effectively aa If II never were.
Thus I. ister Sunday becomes the
llrst twenty-three-hour day In United
Statea history.
The most ceremonious observance
will be that at specially Illuminated
Madison 8iinre I'ark. The Police
Band and the Manhattan Borough
Hand will play and the Community
Chorus sing from midnight until I
A. M which will be but two hours.
President Wilson has delegated Mar
cus M. Marks, a pioneer In the day
light saving move, to turn the hands
of the four great Metropolitan tower
clo ks.
In thousands of cities and hamlets.
In fact, every town that Is lurgo
enough to boast of a timepiece In ISM)
public square, similar petty robbenesi
will lie committed on the old Man
with the Scythe In Hie hope that tbo
collected bOUTS so saved will add an
hour In thS morning and another lb
the evening with which lo work fo,
tlie salvation of civilization to pro
dues tha mate rlabi nscasaury tor tho
Alio s on the lighting front.
CANADA TO SAVE DAYLIGHT.
ties. lire like lulled states' tu Me
I'aaaed un.
OTTAWA. Oat., March 10 The
Canadian Havitght saving nin. t-
rsspondlng to the measure which be
Comas effestlve In the t'nlied tttatea
lo-morrow, will i i-.i.- be paaaed
in about a fortnight When the
Senate resumes in April ft. daylight
ssvlng will be the first Important
legislation before It</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87057262/1918-03-30/ed-1/?sp=7&q=daylight+saving</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>TURN THE CLOCK
AHEAD TONIGHT
Just Do Thle When You Go to Bed
Tonight and Then Forget to
Worry About Ttiat Ad
ditional Hour.
GIVES YOU MORE TIME
If You Play Golf Just Think of the
Extra Daylight You'll Have to
Chase Over the
Green.
JUST DO THIS AND BE CONTENT.
8et all clocks and timepieces ahead
One hour Just before retiring Saturday
night.
Those who are awake at 2 a. m.,
Sunday, may wait until that hour to
set their timepieces ahead one hour.
Ahead—-forward—one hour. Under
stand this and do it, and having done
it, be content, nor worry any more
about it.
This simple Instruction, obeyed so
thoroughly that every timepiece in
the oountry la thus changed one hour
ahead, will carry out the law and pre
vent any confusion whatever. Every
phase of life will move ahead with the
cloaks—trains, street cars, business,
religious services—everything. The 9
o'clock trains Sunday morning will
leave at 9 o'clock by the clock. The 7
o'clock atreet cars will run at 7 o'clock
by the clock—everything will be Juet I
as it Is now, by the clock. And the riotic
clock will be the only thing to rely on
as
It Is now. Just what!his
the clock says, after It has been turned
ahead one hour, that will be the time,
and the time for everything, Just as It
is now. There will be no change in
anything except the clocks and
watches, and no one need pay any at
tention to the fact that they have been
moved one hour ahead.
Complete plans for the daylight sav
ing system, which' goes into effect to
morrow have been announced by fed
eral officials and the nation's workers
are ready to push the hands of the
•clock one hour ahead to assist Uncle
Sam In hig fight for liberty.
Every city in the country, every
town and village, everything is in
readiness for the new system, a sys
tem that will save the nation thou
sands of tons of coal daily as well as
assisting the working man, the shop
girl and the laboring clasa as well as
the busy office man.
What this plan means to the nation
can be described in a few words. In
the first place It means the conserva
tion of the fuel supply. Secondly,-it
gives the average man more time to
devote to gardening, which In turn
means a "bigger supply of food for the
nation and, thirdly, it means a more
healthy nation.
The work of the masses will be done
In daylight, where, heretofore, it was
done In the dark a certain number of
hours a day.
Favored by All.
Since the plan was first spoken of
it has attracted the attention of some
of the biggest men in the country.
Efficiency experts have studied the
plans and in very instance have re
turned a favorable report on their
study.
The action has been favored by
President Wilson for the past several
months. Garfield and Hoover have
been ardent supporters of the plan.
There has never been an argument
against the system and every learned
man in the country is of the J.rsllef that
the plan will greatly aid the nation's
savings.
The daylight saving plan will give
the following daily advantages:
One hour or more for outdoor rec
reation. Recreation is a national as
set, an immense force for health and
moral well-being.
Working mothers and fathers obtain
an extra hour for outdoor play with
their children, both summer and win
ter.
One hour less for bad lights in tene
ments.
Lessened eyestrain for workers and
school children due to the use of artifi
cial light.
Smaller risk of accident in indus
trial establishments, because there
jwill he a light hour instead of a dark
one at the end of the working day at
,tlie time of greatest fati-gue and most
{frequent accidents.
Lessened risk of accidents due to
I transportation and traffic conditions,
because the afternoon rush will fall in
iduylight Instead of darkness,
Working girls will be on the way
home in the daylight instead of in the
!dark in winter.
Our last hour of sleep will be sound
ier and more 'beneficial than it is un
der present conditions, because there
will be less light.
General efficiency will, of course, be
•increased by any improvement in the
(health morals and social welfare of
tiie workers and others.
Morning Coolness.
I In summer a cool hour In the morn
jing is substituted for a hot one In
I the afternoon.
I In winter a light hour at the end of
the day is substituted for a dark one.
This is especially valuable com^g as
it does at the time of greatest fatigue,
and is peculiarly valuable in some in
dustries where aocurate eyesight is
essential.
Efficiency is lowest in the later aft
ernoon, the time when- accidents are
roost frequent.
There will be the greatest of all sav
ings—that of hnman materials, as
pointed out above.
Immediate saving in form of reduc
tion of expense for light and heat.
Ultimate saving in the conservation
QPHE DAILY GATE CITY^
of coal and other sources of light and
heat
Possilble reduction in the cost of liv^
ing of those who like to work in their
gardens, utilizing the extra outdoor
hour for this purpose.
A memorandum containing the fol
lowing important reasons tor the uni
versal adoption of the daylight saving
plan, looking at the matter from the
standpoint of war needs, was sent to
the house committee in February:
The training of the national forces
will be expedited, and the practice of
home guards and similar organiza
tions, the members of which have oth
er regular occupations, will be great
ly facilitated.
The production in all
I
plant3
Are Asked to Cover up Bargains If
It is Necessary to Dis
play Posters for Liberty
Bond Campaign.
A
large assortment of posters ad
vertising the third Liberty loan has
been sent to all township chairmen,
by County Chairman Dunlap, for use
in stores and windows everywhere.
The supply for Keokuk will be dis
tributed, probably by boy scouts,
throughout the business district and
it is hoped that merchants will give
them a very prominent position in
their windows, as the way to help can
the kaiser.
Some of these posters are works ot
the highest art, and some arevnot so
artistic. Some are in black and white
and some are in colors. All of them
are attractive and have a lot of force
of appeal in them.
"These posters were not designee!
to harmonize with the color scheme of
the milinery or the hardware in the
store windows," said Chairmfen
windows, even if they do hide some
mighty good bargains in spring styles
jor some goods formerly eight dollars
and now down to ninety-eight cents.
Raising three billion dollars to win
the war Is not exactly a matter of do
ing things conveniently, you know."
Tax Slackers.
St. Paul Pioneer Press: Collectors
-fniSrternal
revfnue.alln0Unce th^
,'^Wr
GATE
which
ore making materials for war use, in
creased, and the conditions of work
for their employes would be improved.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1918-03-30/ed-1/?sp=2&q=daylight+saving</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>If you do so understand the daylight-saving-
law, and there are many
who are puzzled, do .not worry. Just
before going- to bed tonight advance
your clock one hour that Is. make
It an hour fast and then forget It
Go about 'your business as usual.
You will notice no difference or
change, except that, the sun will rise
later and will set later. The even
ings will be an hour longer.
Under the Jaw. all of the clocks of
the nation must be. advanced one 'hour
at 2 o'clock' tomorrow morning-.
There, is. no need' of staying, up until
2 o'clock, however: you can turn the
clock up Just aa well before, going to
bed.
Here's a lip.
If perchance you are prone to stay
out late Saturday night be sure and
tell wlfey the time' when you come
in. before the clocks are turned up,
otherwise you will be an hour worse
off. 'for official time will akip from
2 to 3 o'clock in an Instant tomorrow
morning-.
If -you fail- to advance jrour docks
and, watches on hour before, going to
bed tonight .you will be an hour be
hind .the country and everybody else
tomorrow. Tou will get to Sunday
school or church an hour late, and
your meals will be off schedule. If
you do not realise this Sunday, you
will be on hour late getting- to work
Monday morning.
Those who have to work on Satur-
Tbere is no occasion for the slightest confusion in
the matter of daylight saving, which begin tomorrow.
All you have to do is when you go to bed tonight, set
your clock oxK hour ahead. Get up at the regular time,
BY THE CLOCK, and proceed as usuaL The simplest
statement of the whole thing is set the clock arc hour
ahead and follow the clock.
HaYe7f aDatefor
2:30 Ton new Mora?
BetYouDon'tKeepIt
Til meet you at 2:30 o'clock,
in the morning,' said one man
to another in front of Tho Tlmea
today.-"
Tes No you won't either."
"Why, you -poor fish. You can
certainly be there at 2:S0.
"Wrong-. Archie. Follow to
closely. There will be no 2 JO in
the morning. When the daylight
savings law goes into effect at
2 o'clock the hands on the clock:
will "be moved around one hour to
3 o'clock. So there will be no
ha'.." past two." l
-Welt I'll be
day nights will ,jct 'a short night, as
the' clock will Jnmp' from 2 to 3
o'clock.
Sleep Henr Less.
If you do not have to work to
night you will get an hour's less
sleep than usual, unless you go to
bed an hour earlier than usual to
make up for' the hour the clocks will
skip. If you turn up the clock an
ALLEYLAWMAY
BESTOW)
hour before) g-otag- to bed and then go
to bed accordingly, you wlti get the
usual night's sleep. For instance. If
the usual bedtime is 11 o'clock, turn -the
clock up one hour at 10 from 10
to 11 and go. to bed. The only'
necessary change for you then under,
the daylight saving- law has been I
made, and you have BO'further wor-l
ries.
The. Sunday morning- newspapers
will- have to speed up tomorrow
momlnsr. as will the milkman anA S
other early hour servitors, to make!
up for the hour that skips away at
2 o'clock. The newspapers will have!
to get an early start for press times
after 2. o'clock.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88064305/1918-03-28/ed-1/?sp=1&q=daylight+saving+time&st=text&r=0.165,0.267,0.663,0.792,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Daylight Saving is
Law Of Land.
r- Don't make any dates for 2:30
t, Sunday morning, March 31, be.
st cause there ain't gonna be no
ill sich animal. In fact, there will
le be no 2 o'clock. At 60 seconds
le after 1:59 it will not be 2 o'clock
but 3 o'clock. Similarly, if you
contemplate any sort of engage
ment, business or social, for 1:30
Sunday morning Oct. 27, you
g had better make plain which
v "1:30" you mean, because there
n is going to be two of 'em on that
y day. Exactly 60 seconds after
1:59 a. m. Sunday morning, Oct.
27, it will not be 2 o'olook, but
1 o'clock again.
That is what President Wils'i
n did Tuesday, March 19, when he
n affixed his signature to the day
light bill which had already been
passed by congress. As a result,
the Muniversally accepted plaint
d that life is growing more com
plex every day, has another sup
porting argument.
However there is going to be
very little confusion, after all.
Just remember to do this, and
you'll be all right:
Before you go to bed on the
night of Saturday, March 30, set
every watch, alarm clock, grand.
father's clock, cuckoo clock or
other timepiece in the entire
house, one hour ahead.' This is
going be done in every house
hold in the entire United States.
On the morning of Sunday, March
31 when you awake, the change
will have been accomplished.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030431/1918-03-24/ed-1/?sp=58&q=daylight+saving+time</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Daylight Saving Is Simplicity Itself
How Ben Franklin s Idea Conceived in 1784, Just Made Into Law Here, Will Affect
Folks After Easter and Save Millions to the Nation
10
By WM. ARCHIBALD FERGUSON,
Secretary of the National Daylight Sar
ins Association.
ON Ihc coming Apwl 1 more people
in the United Slates will probably
be April fool vietims than on any previ
ous or future April 1, for Congress lias
decreed that at 2 o'clock on the morning
of March 31 the hands of the clock shall
be turned forward one hour; in other
words, the United States will then begin
to live under the davlight saving plan,
and doubtless thousands will forget to
make the change.
Every individual who is wise Jind hates
to be fooled will before retiring on the
evening prior to Kaster Sunday, March
31, see to it that not onh his watch but
every clock in the bou.se is turned for
ward one hour. Otherwise on Sunday he
will find the Easter services half over be
fore he arrives at the church, and on
Monday morning, April 1, VMS, rising
an hour late, if he is a commuter he will
miss his morning train by an hour and
be greeted at the factory or office with
such remarks as "April fool!" "You day
light blacker! You forgot to turn your
watch ahead, eh 7'' and all day long he
will be the butt of many jokes.
May Wait Lone for Dinner.
If lie starts for home at the tame hour
as usual and has not during the day tele
phoned his wife to turn the clock ahead
be will have a long wail tor dinner. One
thing Is certain, hotvivcr. that before he
retires that night crry member of his
household will know that the daylight pav
ing plan is in effect and that the people
of the United States are living an hour
ahead of sun time.
The daylight sating idea U almost as
Id as the United States it-elf and our
country can rightly claim the credit for
all the many advantages which will act-rue
from it, not only in this country bat also
in those countries which anticipated the
United Slates in its adoption, for it was
Benjamin Pranklm who Iirst conceited
the idea.
On an early morning walk along the
Etreels of Imdou in 17.S4 the thought Iirst
came to him, and in passing if on to the
world at large he said:
''In a walk through the Strand and Tit et
ttrect one morning at 7 o'clock I ob.-Ttcd
then; was not one shop open, although
it had been davlight ami the sun up
above three hours, the inhabitants of
lxndon choo.-iug voluntarily to live by
candle light and sleei by sun-bine; and
yet often complaining :t little absurdly of
the dnty on candles and the high price
of tallow.''
Soon thereafter in the Jtwrnal Je
Faris he publL-hcd an article, later ap
pearing among his es-ays under the title
4An Economical Project," which further
elaborated the advantages of daylight sav
ing; namely, of "Turning the clock for
ward an hour" so that everybody would
live one hour longer by davlight and one
hour less by artificial light.
Beaten Repeatedly in Britain.
Tor many years in England in the
last century Sir William Willctt annually
introduced his davlight sating bill in Par
liament and annually the bill wa- de
feated amid laughter and ridicule.
In 1915 Germany tirst adopted the plan
to speed np the war production and io
benefit by the tremendous saving in fuel
consumption. France and England and
nil other European countries except Rus
sia soon alter followed her example.
Since its adoption in Europe, the.
United State.-, Canada and Mexico have
been out of harmony, so far as time was
concerned, with European countries, to
their loss not only in business, for the
stock exchanges of Ixindon and Paris un
der the new plan were closed before the
exchanges of New York and I tost on were
open, but also as regards the tremendous
savings pos-ible in light bills, which, it
is estimated, annually will run from V0,
000,000 to $50,000,000 in the United
Sfates alone.
The plan has been ardently advocated
in this country since May, Wlfi, by the
Merchants Association of this city, cham
bers of commerce of Boston, Rochester,
Philadelphia, Chicago and Pittsburg, the
United States Chamber of Commerce,
Washington, D. C, and the National Day
light Saving Association, of which Marcus
M. Marks, former Borough President of
Manhattan, is the president. Mr. Marks
has often been called the '"'father of day
light saving in this country."
To illustrate the effect of the. plan, let
us follow Jack Hurryup, a New York
commuter, through his first business day
under the new regime.
Mr. Hurryup is a habitual reader of
The Scn, and accordingly he knows he
should on the evening of March 30 turn
his watch and clocks ahrad one hour be
fore he retires at 9 o'clock. But on the
night of Easter Sunday he goes through
the house from the kitchen to the
roof and advances each clock one hour
and is surprised when he arritis iu his
bed chamber and looks at his watch to
lind that he is retiring at 10:1.1 instead
of i:15 his lirst shock from daylight
saving.
The alarm dock rings louder than
usual the next morning and he. jumps out
that several of his friends to whom he
telephones have not yet arrived at the
office, but are expected auy minntt.
At 1 o'clock, his usual hour, he hurries
to the restaurant for luncheon and finds
a slim crowd. Upon returning to the of
fice all is running smoothly and at quar
ter of 5 he closes his desk to catch the
5:15. As he passes through the gate at
the Grand Central he sees the same fa
miliar crowd starting on their nightly
journey home.
Ed, Kill and Dick are on hand for the
nightly game of poker, .lack and his
friend Ed were the losers in the game,
for they spent most of their time joking
Bill and Dick for being April fools aud
having missed the train in the morning.
Alighting from the commuters' special
in the country, he is happily pleased to
note that it has not vet begun to grow
BENJAMIN FRANKLIN
jr FROM THE ENGRAVING OF THE DUPLESSIS' PORTRAIT OF 1778
Noted American philosopher is the father of daylight saving.
of bed at C:.'J0, leans out of the window
and noles that the sun is ju-t ri-ing, and
then realizes that he is really getting up
one hour earlier by the sun, although the
alarm went off at the usual hour.
He rushes through his bath and his
breakfast and runs for the train. When
he arrives at the station he is surprised to
find many of his pals missing. The train
pulls in and he runs to his customary scat
in the smoker: the table and the cards
are there, but only one plajcr besides
himself. He greets Ed .(ones, who
boarded the train at the station, above
with:
"Good April fool joke on Bill and
Dick! Guess they forgot to turn their
watches ahead last night. We'll have
some sport with them to-morrow."
Mr. Hurryup piles into the subway
aud is astonished to lind a seat at the
Grand Central, his second shock from
the daylight saving. "Guess a lot of peo
ple are fooled by this daylight saving
this morning," he mutters to himself.
He arrives at the office, looks at the
clock to see whether he has consumed the
usual time on his journey down town and
is surprised to find that he is arriving
at 8:1.1, the exact time at which he took
the tram at his station. Shock No. 3.
No oflice boy in sight. He rings for his
stenographer and she greets him with a
hearty "Good morning He tells her
to get the porter immediately and turn
that oflice clock ahead one hour.
He finds no mail on his desk and con
cludes that the letter carrier is also one of
the daylight saving April fo;Is.
The morning runs on as usual except
dark and that the sun is still shining
brightly at 0 o'clock. "We fooled ton to
day. Old Sol, and will keep fooling you
until November 1," he says to himself.
Arriving at the house he goes to the
cellar, and finding that he need not turn
on the lights he gels out the lawn mower
and bis garden tools.
"This daylight sating is all right," he
calls up fo Mary; ''don't hurry to get on
the dinner. I am going to mow the lawn
and wotk in the garden until sundown."
After an hour's work about the grounds
.lack comes in to dinner and he anil Mary
agree that daylight saving is the greatest
boon ever conferred upon New York com
muters. The chief benefits of the plan, as
proved by the experience of England,
France and other European countries
where it has been in force, may be gen
erally summarized under three heads:
Eirst General health of all people
benefited by reason of an added hour of
daylight in the late afternoon, which has
been and will be u-ed for outdoor recre
ation and exercise.
Second Increased production of food
stuffs through the stimulating cultivation
of home gardening.
Third Money saved in lighting bills:
each householder will burn artificial light
one hour less each day, provided, of
course, he continues his usual habits of
retiring at night.
The report of the summertime commit
tee appointed by the British Parliament
in September, 1!1G, to inquire into the
social and economic results of the sum
mertime act shows that the extra hour of
dat light was generally ucd for the pur-po-e
of outdoor recreation and pursuit's,
and, in particular, for the cultivation of
home gardening.
The athletic dubs reported that the
cricketers, bowlers, golfers and tennii
players took full advantage of the extra
hour of light, and swimming pools and
playgrounds were utilized to full capac
ity. Iu view of the national agitation last
year, which is being renewed now, for
the cultivation of home gardens to in
crease the production of food the inaugu
ration of the daylight saving plan iu this
country will undoubtedly very greatly
stimulate home gardening, particularly in
the neighborhood of the great cities. In
New York city alone there are 1,000.000
daily commuters. Should only one-half
of them use the extra hour of daylight
which the plan will give in cultivating
home gardens there will bo 3,000,000 extra
hours utilized weekly in gardening and
during the seven summer months in which
the plan is in operation 2,000,000 days of
extra work and time will be spent by
these 500,000 commuters in the cultiva
tion of gardens.
What It Means in Potatoes.
It has been estimated that if the av
erage commuter wpre to work a plot of
land only 20x-10 feet, which would le
about I-50lh of an acre, and planted it all
to potatoes, on the basis of 300 bushels
per acre each commuter would he able
to rai-e from four to live bushels of pota
toes; on this basis half of the commuters
of New York city would add to the potato
crop during 191S approximately 2,500,
0011 bushels.
The saving in lighting bills ami in fuel
u.-ed for producing electricity and gas
wdl be tremendous. Public Service En
gineer Robert L. Bruuct of Providence,
If. I., has carefully estimated this saving
and fixed the amount during the period of
live mouths, which the plan originally
contemplated, at $-10,000,000, and tiie
amount of coal sated at 1,000,000 tons.
This sating will he unitersal as every
hou-eholder will u-e one hour les- of aili
licial light daily under the new plan.
Other additional benefits will be the re
duction of traffic accidents due to Ici-cncd
tran-poriation of pa'.sengers under arti
ficial light, reduction of the danger of eye
strain on account of the lessened amount
of reading and work done under artiticial
light and more lime for open air military
drilling.
The davlight sating hill as signed by
President Wilson on March 19 provides
lhat the plan shall go into effect at 2
o'clock antemeridian time on Sunday
morning, March 31, at which time clocks
and watches, probably upon a signal
flashed from the United States Naval
Observatory at Washington will be
turned ahead one hour. Comparatively
very few individuals, unless by design,
will be conscious w hen the change is
made. "This hour was selected by reason
of the fact that at 2 o'clock in the morn
ing the number of railroad trains actually
en route is smallest,
Nobody Will Be Inconvenienced.
Nobody will be seriously inconte
ilienced, unless on Easter Sunday morn
ing or on the night previous individuals
forget to turn their clocks and watches
forward an hour, as the result of which
omission they may find at some time dur
ing that daj- that they arc one hour be
hind the rest of the country.
The remarkable thing about the effect
of the movement is that practically no
class of business will be injured; the only
exception is the open air moving picture
exhibitors-, who under the new plan will
be. unable on account of the sun's setting
an hour later to begin their performance
as early as they have been accustomed in
previous years, which may result in a
loss of patronage. The ordinary business
man, as far as bis business is concerned,
will not be affected in the slightest, ex
cept that he will be more often tempted
this summer to go to the baseball game
which will begin at -1:30 o'clock instead
of 3:30 and to run down more often to
the beaches for a dip before dinner.
Everybody under the new regime will
continue his old habits rising, working,
dining and retiring at the same hours;
we will still live by the clocks and give
the laugh to the cob.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1918-03-16/ed-1/?sp=1&q=act+change+changes+Clock+daylight+daylight-saving+HOURS+law+Saving+standard+time</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>DAYLIGHT SAVING TIMl
3HOURS
VASTED
lYLJGHT
r" I'nY
8HOUR WORKDAY
FREE
LIGHT
HOURS

ItlGHI
These charts show vividly how the daylight saving plan will give j
everybody more "free hour#" of daylight. You've heard this: "Well,!
there are just so many hours of daylight in a day and you can't change j
'em." But wait?the daylight hours before your work-day itarts are
so-called "wasted hours"?you ?leep them away or spend them getting
ready to go to work. The daylight saving plan merely "shifts" an
hour of daylight to the "free hours" after work, when you can use it.
The tables is based on the average June day and the workday from
8 to 5 includes an hour for lunch.
Moving the Clock.
The clock will be set forward one
hour at 2 a. m., March SI, according
to the House bill. At the same hour
on October 27, the clock will be set
back.
The present standard time rones
will remain in effect.
Both changes will take place on
Sunday mornings so that the least
possible wrench may be given to
the industrial fabric of the nation.
But even at that on the railroads
alone there will be some 1.000 pas
senger trains and 5.000 trains run
ning on the tracks when the change
comes, and 1,698.SIS railroad clocks
and watches must be set forward
to keep traffic moving and prevent j together. At present In summer
accidents. In 1883. however, a sim- j London closes as New York opens,
ilar change from local to standard i More time for golf, amateur base
time went into effect on 100,000 ball and tennis.
miles of railroad without a single
mishap.
Benefits of Plan.
The following benefits will be
reaped by the daylight-saving plan:
Saving of one to one and a half
million tons of coal per year, ac
cording to Fuel Administration es
timates.
Increased food production by sub
urban gardeners.
Less traffic accidents.
Improvement in health of all the
people. More fresh air. Women
workers will return from work in
daylight.
Speeding up of freight transpor
tation by giving extra hour at docks
and terminals.
New York and London Stock Ex
changes will be open for one ho'
:i;
Nation Moves Clocks Up
One Hour Easter Sunday
Daylight Saving Bill Passes House by Big Ma
jority as War Measure?Some Opposition
from Farming Communities.
Clocks all over the oountry will
be set ahead one hour, beginning
March 31, under the so-called day
light-saving bill, pessed yesterday by
the House, 252 to 40.
Senator Calder, author of the
ure In the upp?r braftch iftf Congress,
said the House amendments would
be agreed to, so that a conference
would not be necessary.
Provisions of Bill.
The bill provides that at 2 o'clock
p. m. on the last Sunday In March
each year, clocks all over the country
which affect any operations of the
Federal government, or railroads,
i shall be set ahead one hour. At 2
j o'clock p. m., the last Sunday in Oc
j tober of each year, they are to be
i retarded one hour.
j All business relating in any way
U.S. MAY TAKE
1 OVER PACKING
I PLANTS NEXT
Certain to Consider Gov
ernment Ownership of
This Industry.
J Congress will take up the consid
eration of permanent government
ownership or control of the packing j
industry before the present session
ends, according to all indications yes- j
terday. Information has been receiv
ed by members of the Senate to the
effect that the Federal Trade Com- j
mission is to make recommendations
for government ownership of the
packing industry. It is understood
that these recommendations will be
made at the conclusion of the pres
ent investigation which the Federal
Trade Commission is conducting.
Henry Veeder, general counsel for
Swift Co., yesterday filed a pro
test with Vice President Marshall,
Speaker Clark and other leaders in
Congress against the proposed
amendment to the search warrant
law recently requested by Francis J.
Heney, special investigator for the
Federal Trade Commission. The pur
pose of the amendments, the pro
test sets forth, is to legalise such
raids as that recently undertaken by
Heney at the offices of Mr. Veeder
in Chicago. It would make conclu
sive, the protest declares, the de
cision of a district judge issuing the
search warrant, and bars all appeals
until the purpose of the seizure has
been accomplished.
Veeder points out that (he Circuit
Court of Appeals, in his^ ease, held
void the search warrant under which
his office was raided, yet if the dis
trict judge's decision had been final,
as proposed by the Heney amendment.
Veeder would have been despoiled of
his papers without redress.
He suggests that if some agent of
the Comptroller of the Currency were
to assert In an illegal affidavit and
deposition that the money in the larg
est banks in Chicago and New York
was used as a means for the commls
sion of various felonies, such as im
proper speculation or attempted brib
ery of a bank examiner, a district
judge, under the proposed amend
ment, could issue a warrant for the
seizure of all the money in the bank
vaults, holding that "probable cause"
had been found. Thu*, without
chance of appeal, a government offi
cial and a district Judge could disrupt
banking operations of the entire coun
i try for months while even the Su
preme Court of the United States
i would stand powerles* to give relief
until after trial of the accused bank
officers.
k
to the Federal government will be
conducted on the time set. Further
Inducement for Its use by everyone
u liven in designating the times In
tMe various sones as United fctates
Standard F-astern time, TTnlted States
Standard Central time, etc.
Inasmuch as commercial and labor
organizations the country over have
petitioned for the bill, Congress ex
pects a general agreement with the
law everywhere. The five sones are
to be fixed by order of the Inter
state Commerce Commission. But it
Is directed in the bill to have "due
regard" for present railroad classi
fications. The unofficial understand
ing is that no important change is
to be made in present arrangements.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038411/1918-03-16/ed-1/?sp=15&q=daylight+saving+time</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>)AYLIGHT SAVING
TO GIVE WORKERS
TIME FOR PLAY
'hysicians Believe Move Will
Do Much to Better the
Health of Many
Men who like the great outdoors.'
ho like to leave the offices for a
alk. a little fishing trip nnd a round
f golf—to-day praised the passage 1
t the daylight-saving bill by Con- j
ress.
Physicians here to-day also were j
f the opinion that tho new sched- j
le. to become effective Easter Sun
ay, will do much for thd healUi j
fa great number of workers who'
or the first time will have a chance
3 get out into the parks and fields,
fter a day's work.
Businessmen generally tli rough-
out the city this afternoon declared
that the changing of hours would
be accomplished without interrupt
ing or hurting trade. It was said
that tho change would mean little
or nothing to the larger mills ahd
munitions plants, where three shifts
of men now ure engaged in working
throughout the twenty-four hours, j
No difficulty will be experienced in
trolley car schedules, it was said at
the offices of the Harrisburg and
'cross-river traction companies and
the turning of the watch will do
the trick. i
Theaters, railroads and every bus-
iness house in the city will operate
according to the now schedule, and,
therefore, it was pointed out, there
can be 110 confusion after a man
has once reset his watch.
Summed up, Mr, Littlefleld says:
"The bill provides tor an hour
advance in standard time at 2
o'clock a. in. on the last Sunday
in .March of each yefcr and at
a. m. the lust Sunday in October
uie standard time shall be retarded
one hour. Eleven countries have
adopted the summer daylight sav-
ing plan. The first was Germany,
then Great Britain, France, Austria-
Hungary, Italy, Sweden, Denmark,
Norway, Holland, Portugal and Au-/
stralla. London, England, saved
200,000 tons of coal during a sum
mer. In England in five and one
half months $12,000,000 in coal '.vere
saved, and In France $10,000,000. It
is estimated that in the United States
$10,000,000 can be saved in light
bills. The hour of daylight con
served by the proposed law can be
used by industrial workers throug
out America for gardening and agri
cultural work. This will be a most
important gain. We are sure of a
great shortage in farm labor this
summer and something must be done
to offset the probable loss in pro
duction of farm products. The hour
saved for daylight every day in April.
May, June, July, August, September
and October will be of inestimable
value in stimulating the dwellers in
cities and towns to interest them
selves in the production of garden
truck."PASS DAYLIGHT
SAVING BILL;
AWAITS WILSON
Clocks All Over Country Will
Be Turned Ahead
One Hour
Wusliington, Mar. 16—The House
of Representatives, by 252 to 40. yes
terday passed the Senate daylight
saving bill, under the terms of
which, when it receives the signa
ture of President Wilson, it'will be
required that all the clocks in the
United States be turned ahead one
hour at 2 a. m. 011 Sunday, March
31, and remain advanced one hour
until 2 a. m. on the last Sunday in
October.
Under the bill parsed by the
Senate the limit was, fixed as the
last Sunday in September. The
House amendment extending the
daylight saving one month was
adopted upon representations by-
Fuel Administrator Garfield that a
great amount of l'uel would be con
served thereby. It is expected that
the Senate will concur in the amend
ment to-morrow.
Five standard time zones for th
United States will be fixed by the
Government, according to the bill,
and it is made mandatory upon the
railroads to follow the standard
time.
By the passage of the bill, tho
United States joins with England,
France, Switzerland, Portugal and
the three Scandinavian countries in
adopting a method of economy and
efficiency first taken by Germany
during the early days of the war.
Millions of tons .of coal have been
saved in these countries, it was
stated to the House to-day by the
supporters of the measure, by the
simple means of turning the clock
ahead over a period of five or six
months a year.
England reports a saving of 12,-
000,000 tons up to date. Several
Representatives who espoused tha
bill admitted that when it was first
proposed they considered it silly.
But, they said, when they came to
examine its virtues they fell enthu
siastically behind it.
Provided the President signs it,
and there is little doubt that he will
do so quickly, the daylight-saving
bill will have the effect of turning
us all out of bed an hour earlier
than we have been accustomed-to
arise and of sending us back again
accordingly. The use of fuel at
night will be conserved by the clos
ing of establishments at 11 o'clock
which ordinarily do business until
12 o'clock. By the clock on the wall
it will still be 12 o'clock, but by
the moral conviction it. will be 11.
Officials of the Chamber of Com
merce and the Bourse, two of the
many local organisations which car
ried the light for the daylight-sav
ing bill into the very halls of Con
fess. were jubilant on receipt of
the news that the legislation was
so near. Ernest T. Trigg, president
of the Chamber of Commerce, said:
"This is very gratifying to us. By
a readjusting of working hours the
war industries will be speeded up
materially and more time for the
cultivation of war gardens will re
sult."
Emil P. Albrecht, president of the
Bourse, said:
"This legislation will enable work
ers to get better results out of their
daily efforts, as they will be in bet
ter tune for speeding up operations
in the early daylight hours of the
summer months. In such a large
manufacturing center as Philadel
phia the gain in efficiency in the
various war work lines will be tre
mendous. Only on Monday last the
directors of the Bourse urged upon
Congress for the second time within
two months the necessity for this
change."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1918-03-31/ed-1/?sp=8&q=daylight+saving</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>MASTER CLOCK AT
OBSERVATORY NOT
TOBE.SHIEAD
At -It o'clock' this morning, the
TfjiFferf States Naval Observatory will
flash otfer America the first "artifi
cial noon" signal in the history of
the nation.
To'all Intents and 'purposes; the
tTme of th "nashsCJrjjoel-riotf,- ln
accordance with the inaadatr of-Con-
gresa which" ordered 1 all official
clocks' move a forward one., hour at 2
o'clock 4hls, moraine, but out on
Georgetown Heights, at the Naval
Observatory. It will still bo 11. a. m.
k meridian time by the uaJtlWa stan
dard" clock.
.The Xaval Observatbrr. It was slid
today, will probably be the only-offl-cial
"spot on the American, map. where
trie master clock wll continue run
ning, according ,to true time, and con
swjueritly. on'e. hour behind the rest
of tiie country. The answer to this
apparent; indifference tff the orders of
Congress lle 1nt&e.Jle.iJeaT;e adjust
ment of Amricjt;rUndrd tlrrfe-plece
t me enrorjoryTper.ifp5g dayy sup
plies the pojnOnentCjia 'Atoerlcan
ships far at. jsja'wlth'' ihe.ytandara
Urn, or the'Werfdlan not Washington.
LleuU JU -Patton,, -NU and
Time .Kspert "8iuct"tlie Observa-
iqry,- sent.s5ur-iaeiaar;,.tBne-nasn .un
der the old ByJm-atJlO' o'clock la".
night. ThlattlmaVltiab'- neae'f rated tn
efery PJ(rtJgr-v-eijtounty over
glgantlo- ntrvyte3 of -telegraph
wires aba IfevfrM -ifift-flaahed' East:
V.est. North, and Booth by- wireless
fronvtht: Arlington rad)6tat!ob.
Ordlh'arrlly", the Obr.vatory. aends
out but-oW tlrae-aiiH. a.,dy. That
IsrrvenLat-QOon, Xwdjlsthes. (bough,
were sent oufc yesterday one at soon
.and- the'Bthr 'ajklO. 1 ra, Thelast
'flash wj((jspf -flnal- warning! to
get vbrymUtJinity'lbior turn
ing thejn VsS&Sfc,1.'?..
Alttrbngh. -Congress- t 2 a.,m. as
'the-jMsaVJo mjtf.he.-3JeW" daylight-saving
plan inu&i'cperatton, comparatively-
.fevfjsUjcKs. -were, turned- up ,at
that hour. Host of the mantleplecfc
chronometers and family alarm
flocks got their turning-tip, mV bed
time, last night, and, America, for .the
most partj.awDlie- this Paaday- morn
ing In accordance- -with the new
schedule
Pome hour had o be set. however,
'for; the' use' of railways and other In
dustries where lime is -always,an .Im
portant factor, and the wee sma,'
hours of this morning were' chosen
by .Congress ..because, less, .confusion
was liable to result from a change
at that Jjour, when traffic, Is compara
timely quiet and- the world- alee.
than at any other hour of the whole
twe"hty-four.
Tie. average tune-piece,
no matter
how excellent and well-balanced It may
be. can be turned up one hour by hand
wiuwui iipw ounw w iu wra.
1U. Art Ac-am fntM.ri friA ViM tf f h
some one eVen touch the liands of the
bjjc jtn4ter clock at th XavakObeerva
'tory and" .the observa.tory scientists
'urobably'vIH have to' stay -up' alt -Sight
looking for the trouble. Those observa
tory clocks are looped up with a most
amazing tangle of electric wires, and
turning them forward an hour Is a, task
t that wotihi reejnlre days,"of effort, be
cause 4h Job would .have to be done by
electricity and by very slow, 'degrees:
For that reason, the JS'tTal Observa
tory will ran its clocks according to I
stellar time aO "during the present, artl
flqial-time period.- and in that way
any possible maladjustment of these
'dejlcate, temperamental time-pieces
WUT be avejad?
OlfieiaMy 'Enacting-Daylight Saving Xaw
mmmUWMmmmmWmWMK&BMBSnVtR' ''mmSaBiaf -J&r X7(P i" ft&ZMmmWmW
slslslslslslslsVlzsBBtiHBBiKK -y.1ls9isBr &Jye -"Vti tr- -IslsV H
isisisBsisisisKsHHisHisY"-:os7V'" OammmF )itX. lli VtaHHsl
mWmmwWipmWJm"jkk' mm
mmmmmmlMaWI&W$m :M
.isisisisisH.L-f?diRflB Hw&iV
isisisisisisisisisisisiisisisisisKBLkH9BKifBHBiBk t ktBS'UmmmwMm' -ti-.mmmmKWF coX. ,V aH
HLwissBilivsisisisftki ,7'" Ammmmm
mmmwWQmwI27Ili3uWmmWWmm&mWWnwwwwwwmWSS&
mwMwMwMwMwMWMwMwKmwMwmMwMwMwMmMmwmuWmmmmWmmmmwKmwM
frite'asiO.-B. Watts, photographed as he advanced the-handa ot ihc-transmitting dock-.ot the, United
State Naval Observatory. This clock announces, the time for more tharhal the world. Its flash goes to the
Arinfetori wireless towers and the Key Wes't and Chicago naval stations, while the Western Union and
Postai -wires take its- messages as far as thereach! It is the -official 'timepiece of the United States,
bat,n.oV thV standard' clock. The master, clock keeps sidereal-'time," measured by the course of the stars.
No" law of'CoiiBress tan laffect this, but it will be the only clock in the United States outside) of naval
v observatories- whose-fhands,are not subject6 law.
WlTHDllf A HITCH
N D. a SCHEDULES
With Its clocks all comouflaged, j
from the standard chrpnometera. at
the Ttavat -Observatorr down M r-
family-: alarm clockVashlngton. and
the rest of, the. country Is moving
along serenely, today an -hour ahead
of the sun. At X o'clock the sun-
had ,Just gotten overhead.
Washington picked up the new.
I .-t.A4.11 nrndtfa'lli' Tt-lthnilt !nMenti
or noticeable effect, though some
newf boys and some milkmen who hod
failed to rakke an allowance for tie
1 l il
skipping, of an hour when the clocks
moved from 2 to .3. o clock, were 'ate
on tlieir rounds. Most of the milk-'
men solved It, one of them stated, by J
moving the clock up before gotnjr tol
bed", and getting up on the new!
schedule. i
Train schedules In and out oft
Washington Were adjusted practi-'
cally without Incident, trains on the
road at" 2 o'clock k.eeplng art hour i
behind time-to destination.
There was little ceremony atten-1
dant upon the clock moving in Wash-i
ington. In the city's households
clocks were moved at bedtime lastj
nlght,and most residents awoke on
the new schedule. Forgetful ones
were, up hour behind and had to
catch un tortav. In the future the
t average ltisn will be at' work one
M4 ..ra,X sssr
and have an hour more to spade the
garden or" play tenuis.
Daylight saving as war measure
compulsory. It is ilmated .that
the measure will rts-ult In a cut of
M j nat,on., blI1
tor artificial Sight
The change tn the Government de-1
Ipartments, the, a to res, business houses
office's-' of. -Washington will b
affected practically without notice.
Clock were turned up at the close of
business last night, or during the
morning today. The hands on the big
postoffice clock were turned up at
p. ra. this morj-itnsr. the official hour
for the change.
The Senate, however, took time by
thhe forelock yesterday and moved
the Senate clock up at 2 o'clock 'in
tbo afternoon. Senator Caltler of
I Sew York, who sponsored the day-
Jthe clock up there twelve l.mirs be-,
!'u1
fore schedule. Ills performance was I

i ji lAict "iiaiii? niiu iiianuiaL'iiii
.era' Association put the clock ahead
one hour at the clo.r- of business yes-

terday. It was tunfed up by Secre
tary C. J. Colurabuy. It was an
nounced that there would b" no
change ln store or other business
hours in Washington.
Text of Daylight Saving Law
An act to save daylight and to provide, standard time for the United
Be it enacted by the Senate and
United' States of America m. Congress -ossemDiea, mat, ior ine.pur-.
pose of establishing the, standard time of the United States, the ter
ritory of continental Umted States shall be divided .into five zones in
the manner hereinafter provided. The standard time of the. first zone
shall be based on the mean 'astronomical time of the second, .zone, on
the.ninetieth degree; that of the third zone, on the one hundred and
fifthdegree; that, of thefourth zone on .the one hundred and twentieth
degree, ard that of the fifth zone, which shall include only Alaska, on
the" one hundred and fiftieth' degree. That the limits of "each zone shall
K AofmaA hv an nrtloi- nf thp Interstate Commerce Commission, having..
regard for the convenience f commerce and the existing. jucc.tion J
points and division point 'of common .carriers engaged in commerce-J
between the several States' and. with foreign nations, ana sucn oruer
'may be modified, from time to time. r
o Tht within the resnective zones created under the" auth
ority hereof Ihe standard time of the
oi all common earners rengagca in- commerce ikhvbm -mo kici
States or between a State and any of the Territories of the United
State, or'bftween a State or thtfrTerritory of Alaska and any of the,
insular possessions ottlie United States orany lereim countrytflrf
all statutes; orders, rules, and regulations relating, io the time,of,-per-;
formance of any act by anyof ficer or .department of the United States,
whether in the legislative, executive, or, judicial branches of the Gov
ernment, or relating to the tinre within which any rights shall accrue
or determine, or within which any act shall or shall not be performed
by-any person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, it shall
he Understood and intended that the time shall be the United States
standard, time of the zone within which the act is toibe performed.
Sec? 3. ThaJ; "at two" o'clock antemeridian of the last Sunday inj
JIarch of .each year.jhe standard time oi cacn zone snail De advanced
one hour, and at two o'clock antemeridian of the last Sunday in
October in each year the standard time of each zone shall, by the re
tarding of one hour,-be returned to the mean astronomical time of the
degree of longitude governing said zone, so that between the last Sun
day in March at two o'clock antemeridian and the last Sunday in Octo
ber at two o'clock' antemeridian in each year the standard time in each
zone shall be one hour in advance of the mean astronomical time of the
degree of longitude governing each zone, respectively.
Sec. 4. That the standard time of the first zone shall be known
and designated as United States. Eastern Time: that 6f the second zone
shall be known and Designated as United States Standard Central
Time; that of the.third zone shall be Known and designated as United'
States Standard Mountain Time; that of the fourth zone shall be
known and designated as United States Standard Pacific Time; and
that of the fifth, zone shall be known and designated as United States
Alaska Time
Sec; 5. That, all Acts and parts of Acts in conflict herewith are
hereby, repealed.
Approved March 19, 1918.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87057262/1918-04-01/ed-1/?sp=5&q=daylight+saving</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>What became of that hour between
2 a. m. and 3 a. m. Easter morning?
Where did those sixty minutes go
which were abolished from the face of
thd earth?
Thirty-six hundred seconds extermi
nated when the clocks of America
were turned ahead.
Keoktik observed the daylight sav
ing law Sunday morning by turning
the clocks ahead one hour. And every
The earth Is approximately 24,000
miles around. It makes a full turn in
twenty-four hours, or travels at the.
rate of say one thousand miles per
hour. We poor mortals, clinging to
the earth as best we can are being
whirled around at this excessive rate
of speed. We are going some. Yet
Sunday morning at 2 o'clock, when the
clocks were changed, we made an ex
tra jump of a thousand miles in our
mad race. Did you notice the change?
The miser has $200,000 out at inter
est at six per cent. His income from
this is $1.37 every hour of the day.
Sunday morning he made an extra
$1.37 when the clocks were changed.
But when the clock is changed iback in
October, he will lose an equal amount.
The sick man was to be given a pill
every half hour. The nurse had been
instructed to be very careful in fol
lowing out the instructions. Some
body changed the clock and she got all
muddled up as to whether to give the
dying, man two extra pills. It was a
case of life and death. The nurse
fainted and the poor sick man got no
pills all night long. When the nurse
regained consciousness, her patient
had recovered and was out working in
his war garden.
The early worm had become tired
of dodging the early bird every morn
ing, so the worm made his trips over
the top an hour earlier each day. But
the bird observed the new daylight
savings law and met the worm half
way as usual.
A certain man came home at 2
o'clock. Before retiring he changed'
the mantle clock. When it struck the
hour of two he shoved it ahead anoth
er hour and it struck three. Then he
went to bed. In the morning his wife
accused him of coming home at five.
No argument was allowed. She heard
t0
the^cloek strike five. Oh, what's thejold
The clock In West Keokuk, in
Lincoln school belfrey. was hanging
six bells -at seven o'clock Sunday
morning, one of the few sla-ckers in
Keokuk. The hands have since been
changed and the clock is now running
on war time with the others.
What Became of That Hour
That Was Lost Sunday Morn?
Change in Clock Brought
About Some Interesting
and Also Embarrasing
An hour a day gained has its dark
side as well as its light. For instance
rent becomes due an hour sooner. We
are one hour nearer the grave. Life
and fire insurance expires one hour
sooner. The thirst parlors in the dry
towns close one hour earlier. Weeds
have an exta hour to grow in the gar
den.
High noon isn't as high now as It
was before and midnight is not quite
so mid.
The profiteer liaB now another ex
cuse for raising the price. He can
?,mA"°?/"*
ay
a®c°,Vnt
ii OT 3 TV*
time, etc. etc."
it is anticipated that this flag. Pledge to the flag. Flag drill.
will out-rival all others in se- The centennial program as well as
determined. Whoever centennial celebration, and is circular program, "Planting the Cen-
the mh 0f
J. 1- ithe man who stole the chickens. (anniversary of the enabling act of been much in demand as a patriotic
Bloodless people, thin, anemic people,
on Aoril 18, 1818, the state speaker during the past few-months, ver H. Cossart, deceased, was filed
iarge anfl appreciative the.daily program to include salute *t
schools, is making every effort for simple flag drill to be found in the
children throughout the school journals.
to assist in the observance of Planting the Centennial Tree—A
to arrange and give a suit- teacher, which can be made a very
centennial and patriotic program interesting part of the program.
April, which is the: States Attorney Earl W. Wood has,
congress, on April 18
centennial commission has
mended that April 18. 1918, be one to make addresses, including Still
of the dates to be observed this year,
1
become more an l' exercises to be held in the rural dis- yet finds time to give many hours to
of «sh" is^ie cry utter- tricts in the afternoon or evening, the enlightment of the people of his
hv ^rLu
J^he TLeszei^n^ rl I while in the larger schools teachers vicinity along patriotic lines.
If fdltlom of which have
evening at
of the change in
The biggest change comes around
midnight. What used to be today Is
now tomorrow.
Wonder if a fellow died at 2:30 a.
m., Sunday, if the life insurance com
pany couldn't avoid payment by claim
ing there was no such time?
A Keokuk policeman on the night
force left the station one minutes be
fore two Sunday morning and walked
city and village in the United States I f^pidly to the union depot He got
did the same thing. Whatever time it
is now, it was an hour earlier a day
ago. One hour of Sunday morning
must be accounted for somehow, some
where. Who's got It?
there at 3:10, an hour and fifteen min
utes for eight blocks.
A traveling man who arrived In Keo
kuk at 2 o'clock Sunday morning and
walked up the hill to the hotel, found
that it took him over an hour to make
the trip. He wiped the perspiration
from his face and said to the hotel
clerk: "Whew, I knew that was some
hill I was climlbing, but I didn't realize
it was that long."
If a fire had broken'out in the Estes
house at 2 o'clock Sunday morning, it
would have taJcen the department an
hour to get there. By that time the
•fire would be beyond control. But it
didn't.
Children whose bed time has been
8:30 o'clock, will have to go to bed
before it gets dark these evenings.
That's tough on the kids, but war is
war.
Easter Sunday of 1918 can always
be remembered as having but twenty
three hours. We used to think Decem
ber 2,1 was the shortest day of the
year, but the war has changed many
things and now Easter is the shortest.
If shoving the clock ahead one hour
is such a good thing, why not go a
little further and shove the calendar
ahead one month. Why not tear off
April altogether and have May right
now, thus avoiding the April show
ers and have fresh vegetables and
warmer weather right away? Or go a
little further and shove the whole
year ahead. That might see the end
of the war six months behind. Good
scheme for somebody with plenty of
spare time to figure out and suggest
to Washington.
Prisoners whose sentences expire
before October 31, when the clock
will be pushed back again, have bad
their sentences reduced by one hour,
'by the pushing ahead of the clock.
The chickens held a convention
Saturday night to see whether they
would crow by the new time or the
time
"fi* presided, was not in favor of any new
fangled notions. There were a lot of
•he! the young bloods, however, tvho want-
CARTHAGE, ILL., APRIL 1.
1
The annual stunt fest will be held |by Bryant "The Uprising," by Read,
nege gym under the auspices Quotations—To be short readings!
0
I
Grandfather Rooster, who
ed to get up an hour earlier and the
committee decided to purchase an
alarm clock to hang in the chicken
house so that the morning salute
would be properly given.
TIME.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-motorcycle-mania</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042591/1869-01-22/ed-1/?sp=1&q=motorcycle+motorcycles+vehicle+street+race</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>THE VELOCIPEDE.
"Nothing is at.once invented and
perfected," says an old Latin maxim,
the truth f whose application wa.s
made manifest iu the etuiy history
of the velocipctie. Like all things of
earth it lift" loity years iu the
wilderness. It fiitt made its appear
ance in Paris and received notice to
the following effect iu the Journal il,
I'arit.
lure
The date t,r the tvtree
1 Was Ktd that
certain vehicle, invented by M. M
Itlanchard ami Massurier the for
merthe celebrated aeronaut was ex
hi Li ted in roi'iil motion in the Pbc
Louis XII. on July l7, 17X9, in i.rea
ence of many members of the French
academy and a large concourse of
spectators. At the front of the nis
chine was the head of an eagle with
outspread wings, to which was at
tiched the aparatus w ith which the
driver directed its movements. Be
hind him was seated an individual
who gave an impetus, moro or less
rapid, to the machine by pressing
his feet alternately on the ground.
He sat down or stood at discretion.
with his legs half concealed in a soil
of box, where the springs that com
niiimcated movement lo the machine
were evidently placed. The inventor
uhsequcntly transported the vehicle
to V ersailics, and exhibited its capa
bilities in presence of Louis XVI
Maria Antoinette and their court.
There is nothing to show why this
experiment failed, but it is to be sup
posed that it had its defects.
The second appearance was also
n 1808, and public exhibitions were
made of its workings in the Jardin du
uxemliourg, but without fcucccts.
At that time it was mounted on very
low wheels, and the rider had to sup
port himself by placing Lis feet di-
eclly on the ground. Such a mech
anism was of course rudimentary,
and the result was that the invention
was extensively ridiculed and carica
tured, and in these ai chives only do
any traces of the first experiments
mado with this machine iu tho gar
den of Luxembourg exist.
But t'je modern railroad locomo
tive was also sneered at and carica
tured, and so was the modern steam
boat. And the early inventors, who
sought to make the world wiser, were
called disc'ples of the- black art, and
friends of the devil. And more, they
ware socially ostracUed they were
hooted lit and stoned by the mob,
and feometimes hurccd at the stake
But they never ceased f-cheming and
planning, nor was the velocipede to
stop here. Twenty years alter its
first exhibition the velocipede re-ap
pe.tred in Paris. This time, a public
functionary, ona AI. Drunze, peifict-
the machine or twenty veals In-
fore, and again exhibited it in its
improved form. M. llreuze secured
the lider's point of suppoil upon the
axletrees to the two wheels liiHleml
the gioiind, and thus crealtd the
actual modern vclocincde. Thu in
ventor, who belonged to the admin
istration of postollices, also forimd
further idea of proponing this
machine for the useol rural postmen,
being ot greater availability in ll.e
matter of spued and promptness, nnd
the same lime causing tin in less
fatigue. The plan was adopted, but,'
unfortunately, Just in the winter sea
son, when roan' difficulties existed
the way of locomotion. The wheels
slipped about in the hard sand with
advancing, and the enterprise
was Again considered a failure. At
this late day, it would have been
suggested that it was only neccssar)
iron the wheels, or euspt-nd the
of the vehicle during the winter
But the French Government disliked
innovation, and dropped the veloci
pede.
'Three times and out,' is the old say
ing, but not so w ith our subject. A
rewycars on, andtundiscoiiraged, the
velocipede appeared a third time, and
again in an altered form this lime
being a little carriage upon three
wheels, and propelled by the hands
the rider. This machine did not
succeed on account of the diiliculty
guiding it, aud the fatigue it
V
of
of
be
a
be
of
the
a!
cog
is
the
on
end
keep
the
caused the guider. Itis a well-known .so
fact that the muscles of the legs cau lull
used much longer than those of
arms, and, acting upon this hint,
good velocipedes are so arranged
that the action of the arms is merely
complimentary to that of the legs.
This failure was the result of not
attending to this fact.
"The mills of the goiU grind slow
ly, but they grind exceedingly line.''
Science and improvement move like
tortoise, but still they move, as
Galileo said of the world. When a
pebble is dropped in tho water your
loses the tipple. But that little
splash has displaced every drop in
stream, aud the water you see
before you has been completely
changed. The velocipede as il has
been exhibited thus far was an idea
dropped into the mind, and that idea
must grow, and tho mind must lie
revolutionized before its work ends.
the presence of success who is so
bold as to laugh. Ridicule falls
harmless before the iron armor ol
prosperity. Anil tne velocipede
succeeded. Paris, where it was hoot
ed at and frowned flown, now lifts
the prostrate work, aud the thins
despised yesterday is the idol wor
shipped to-day. It is the poetry of
justice, and the two share the tri
umph. The thorouguiares of Paris
thronged with countless riders
the strange creature, and tne
public have wained the velocipede
votaries that they must carry their
lanterns ou their vehicles to avoid
accidents. The mania has spread to
classes, aud to the suburban cities
the capital. In St. Cloud, Vin
cennes, Kngheim, Pantim in Bor
deaux, Marseilles, and the other
principal cities, the people are all
riding this economical species of iron
horse, which requires no feed, har
ness, stable, or groom to care for it.
The velocipede and velocipede
mania has reached America. It
struck New Orleans many yearn sgo.
the inhabitants of that benighted
burgh thought it might be the .''yel
jack" in disguise, andgave it
cold shoulder, lime passed, and
Europe was ablaze with enthusi-
ana astriue ot lueir iavonte
seat,
easo.
try
toot
this
a
been
are
cost
even
feet,
the
are
and
the
is
a
fore
this
ence
steeils. Len the mania reachci
here, it found lis deep in the myste
ries oi "iiianchette.'' With tru
popular fickleness, the "manj -heu.tei
miilUlude diopped the nnstii: stm
Ool, ami vaulted ni'.o the saddle ot
the velocipede. New York, 1'hila
delphiaaud Chicago are nil infected
iNew lork, the Pans of America
is, in this instance, eniuloui of her
model. Divibi-H, lawyers, i reaclu rs.
i
ami editors nave, uiotinicil their iron
wamsteeds with t!iP Nflinn vinnriitu twit hit
ajsianu they mount their favorite bob.
bies. l.eecher has left tf worship
ping nimseii ami mining penance on
ine velocipede liana is praeticino
fi an aeronaut in the same machine
huh uretley is gelling one ret.ly for
the next lecture, season. He potters
are mounting them and gallopiug
around Gotham after items. Ben
nett is fast ltecoming an expert in
this line of horsemanship, with the
idea of escaping from from the horse
whippings which are thrcKtened him
at every corner. And to finish the
iiium, tut: lauies are entering me
lists in the pleasures and excitement
of the new stylo of horsemanship.
eloclpedes are to be met in every
street and in tho park-), public and
private.
1 hiladclphia, staid and quakerish.
has adopted the velocipede with but
little less enthusiasm than New York.
Forney is practicing, and s aie the
young swells ami bloods of the town.
1'he ladies here are also catching the
fever, nnd the broad thoroughfares
the rectangular ei'y bid lair to
rival New York in their exhibitions
the new order of cqucstrianship.
(Jkicago, alert and awake, is not to
outdone in anything, and veloci
pedes arc becoming a matter of every
lay occurrence on our streets. Our
tradesmen and merchants are begin
ning to lay them in for sale, and, as
the fever is catching, by the time the
season opens we will tee them be
coming among our regular iustitu
tions. If the3 are to prove a success,
there is no city ami surrounding
country better adapted to their use
than this a city perfectly level, aud
suriounding country perfectly lUt,
are elements tor the use of this ma
chine best calculated to test its mer
its.
Chicago, as is her wont, is not to
beaten even in velocipedes, and
comes to the rescue with a machine
which dillers from any other extant.
not only in its general appearance,
but in its motive power. This Chi
cago velocipede has three wheels, two
behind and one in front. The hind
wheels ni e considerably the largtst,
being feur feet and two inches iu
diameter, while the front wheel is
only tvto feet aud one half. The
front wheel is for tie puipnsc ol
guiding the machine, nrd is connect
ed by n lever with the lioily, aud
reaching within convenient tlislance
the sent, a straddle inns up liom
axle of the Ironl or guidiug wheel.
"jut a foot from the tiie, which is
surmounted by a lamp. This veloc
ipede is propelled by spring-power,
which works as follows: the
axle of the hind wheels is fastened a
pinion, which is operated upon by a
wheel, five times its size iu diam
eter. Fastened to each tide ot this
large cog-wheel is a dog, which works
a rachet, upon Hie hub of which
ratchet is fastened the centre of the
springs. '1 he other end of the spring
lasleiied to a rod of iron, which
runs through the body of tho veloci
pede. These springs are made of the
very liest jnglisu Mnng steel, two
inches wide, one-tenth of au inch
thick, and nine feet long, and when
wound up their power is estimated at
J.ooo pounds each. Immedi-
a
alely outside ol the spiing, and in
rachet Lub, is fastened erne of the
treadles. The large cog-wheel and
ratchet work loofrC artuud the shaft
which tLcy are placed. The
treadles are two feet loi.g, and reach
the rachet shaft to within con
venient distance lor tne iuot or a
person occupe ing the seat. On the
of each treadle is a klippcr lo
the foot Irom being shoved for
ward. By an ingenious contrivance
wheels can be thiown out of gear,
that the velocipede, even under
headway, can De turned around
within a space of fourteen feet.
The seat has the appearance and
general characteiistics of a buggy
and can carry two persons with
It was designed for the use ol
ladies only, but cau be used by any
body. The grand feature of this.
Chicago velocipede is, that it is work
ed by spring power, and that the
springs can be perpetually wound up
simply using the treadles alter
nately. It only takes oue-toiirth the
power to wind the springs that the
springs exert in unwinding. By
pressing upon the treadle with the
the rachet is turned, on which is
placed the spring, which of course is
thereby wound. It differs from the
Alton invention iu this, that the
springs are beirg continuously
wound by the alternate treadles, aud
can always ba kept in motion;
wLilc the Alton invention runs only
mile and then stops to be wouud
again. This Chicago invention has
tested and all who have seen it
sanguine of its success. The
of one of these machines will be
about $100.
Velocipedes are of various kinds.
Some have two, and others three, and
four wheels all have either
pedals or rests on which to place the
and usually either brakes or
levers to regulate the speed.
is
ion
are
the
val
to
for
an
THE TWO-WHEEL VELOCIPEDES.
The two wheeled velocipedes, oi
bicycles as they are styled, are
intended for the male sex only, and
by far the swiftest machines.
They are usually of wrought iron,
have pedals or reels attached to
front and large wheel, and the
working of which, by a light move
ment of the feetoives the requisite
impulse lo the vehicle. The saddle
poised upon a bar iron, suspended
lew inches nlvovc the top of the
wheel. The hands rest on a
handle in Irontof the machine, which,
working on a pivot, serves as a I al
auclng pole, the equilibrium being
preserved by giving a slight twist to
handle. The brake, which at
stops the revolving motion of
of
of
the
are
the wheel, is applied by means of
sharper twist.
THE THREE WHEEL VELOCIPEDE.
The three wheel velocipede, or
tricycle, is easier to guide and safer
o use than the bicvcle. Its speed.
however, is less rapid still it can Iw
made lo pass a carriage at full trot.
As the fair sex largely palrouize
the tricycle, the seat is more commo
dious than llinlofthe bicycle, havino
sides and backs of wicker, aui
uorse hair cushion to sit upon. The
hind wheels, though large, are light,
end revolve wilh facility. 1 he fore
wheel, winch is smaller, serves to
uidrt the machine, being acted upcu
y means of the handle, which causes
it insttntly to turn in lh direction
indicated lv the rider. The nedals
ere shaped like slippers, which facil
tato the movement of the legs, and
at the same time atlmits of the foot
icing disengagcil instaneously. The
movement required to impel the ma
chine is a perfectly natural one, an
alogous to that of walking. That is.
it requires but the slightest pressure
of the foot, and produces no uuusual
fatigue to the leg. In addition to
these advantages, the largest three
wheeled velocipedes have a bar which
lollows the hue ot the eccentrics at
tuclicd to the pedals and fits on the
axles. By assisting the movement
of this lever, the speed of the vehicle
is considerably increased, aud a
simple pressure against It checks the
rotary movement of the wheel and
tops the progress of the machine.
I his lever is, in fact, both a means
of impulsion and a brake.
THE PRICES.
The prices of velocipedes range
according to their arrangement.
Those that are imported into this
country, range from 880 to $125.
Of course this is exclusive of those
numerous etceteras, such as a grease-
box, india rubber cushions for the
iron bar in front of the machine, on
which the legs rest, and the like.
THE SPEED.
attained by the swifter kind of veloc
ipedes, averages from 12 to 13 miles
an hour; adepts find no diiliculty
whatever in accomplishing 50 miles
within five hours, without once alight
ing from their vehicle. It is record
ed that a couple of amateurs making
tour through a part of France,
challenged each other as to which
could perform the greater distance
within 24 hours. One gave in after
having accomplished 87 miles, the
other went on until he had made 123
miles in the allotted time
THE LABOR TO WORK IT.
It should be understood that, in
impelling a velocipede, the limbs are
not constantly iu motiou, as on level
"round when tho impetus is at the
average rate, or when the machine
ileHcciiiliiio; an incline, tho feet may
be removed from the pedals and the
!'M le Placed ou the bar fixed n
front of the velocipede for this pur
pose. A slight impulsion given from
tune to sullices to keep np the speed
THE ASCENT.
The ascent of any incline greater
than 1 in 2a is said to be imnracti-
cable. When the rider, therefore,
encounters a hill of more than av
erage steepness, he has to dismount
and lead his velocipede by the hand.
which it is said can lie done with al
most me same ease as in carryino an
ordinary walking stick.
AMERICAN MANUFACTURE.
The manufacture of this locomotive
novelty has now commenced in this
country. Americans, with their
usual fertility of invention. Lav
begun to improve on the French
model as above given, ami when
llicte improvements will end. the
archives in the patent office at Wash
ington can only foreshadow. New
York, Philadelphia and Boston have
already started shops for their man
ufacture, while it is expected that
Chicago will soon do the same. The
French models are not only expen
sive, owing to the peculiar shape and
construction of the iron frame, and
consequent diiliculty of forging it,
hut arc heavy, owing to all parts
being solid, and no elective provis
has been made for the removal of
part that may be broken or worn
out.
to
of
a
of
a
AN IMPROVED VELOCIPEDE,
recently patented in New York city,
overcame all the before mentioned
objections to the French model. The
reach or frame of the New York
velocipede is tubular, and thereby
great strength and lightness are secu
red. The bearings are all of compo
sition, or gun metal, and so attached
that when too much worn out thev
may be replaced by others, which
interchangeable, like the parts of
sewing machines and fire-arms. The
of the hinder wheel is bushed
with composition or gun metal and
apis is of peculiar construction.
constituting in itself an oilpot by
ueiog uiauo mouiar and closed at
either end by a screw, on the remo
of which it may be filled with
lard oil. This oil finds it way out
the bearing as fast as required,
through two or three fine holes made
the purpose iu the axle. Another
important feature in the American
velocipede is the arrangement of the
tiller or steering handle, which is
brought well back and sufficiently
high to require the rider to maintain
erect position, with his arms well
back and hands well separated, Ihns
keeping tho chest well expanded,
allowing free play of the lungs.
he stirrups also UiUer from the
Parisian model. These stirrups are
three-sided with circular flanges at
each end and as thev are fitted to
turn on the crank-pins, the pressure
the foot will always bring one
the three flat sides into proper
position. 1 hese nat sides are rough
ened to prevent the foot from slip
ping, and arc so shaped as to permit
use of the fore part of the foot
and bring the ankle joint into nlar.
thereby relieve the knee consid
eratly. making the propulsion much
easier than when the shank of the
foot is used exclusively. The cranks
made adjustable, to suit different
persons, and different kinds of roads
and inclines. The saddle is support
ed on a spring, giving an elastic seat
The brake is exceedingly simple, and
at
put
the
as
the
in
a
to
effective, being composed of a block
of hard wood attached to the under
side of the back: part of the saddle,
which is shaped to form a good brake
or rest for the lower part of the back
of the rider. The spring of the sad
dle being adjusted to suit the rider,
the break-block clears the face or the
hind wheel until it is required to be
used, and then a pressure forward
against the tiller with the hands, and
backward against the after part oi
the saddle with the back, instantly
compresses the saddle spring and
brings the brake into action on the
wheel. Several firms are now en
gaged in the manufacture of this
patent in New lork. Their price is
about $80.
AN ILLINOIS VELOCIPEDE.
This prairie country, almost as
level as a parlor floor, will atlord a
future range for the use of veloci
pedes unrivalled. And it is not
strange that our citizeus are paying
no inconsiderable attention to the
machine. Mr. B. E. Lowe, of Upper!
Alton, has invented a ve!ociede by
which it is claimed he can climb the
steep hill between Upper aud
ower Alton.
RULES FOR MANAGEMENT.
Tho following rules for the gui
dance of beginners have been drawn
up by one of the most ekilltul Par
isian amateurs, aud are hero submit
ted for the benefit of Chicago no-
ices
Run beside your iron horse, lead
ing it, as it were, with your Land, so
as to lamuiarize yourself with its
movements; this will bo an affair of
a few minutes merely. Then com
mence practising with it on a slope,
ami, after mounting it, let it move
forward of its own accord, while you
occupy yourself in stutlying the ef
fects produced by the inclination
which yon give to the balancing pole
or handle of the machine. When
you thoroughly understand the ac
tion of this, place one foot on the
pedal, and follow its movements
wi'.hout assisting them. Iho diili
culty with beginners is to restrain
the unnecessary expenditure of mus
cular force they ordiuaniy perform
ten times the lalor that is requisite
Next repeat tha experiment u level
ground, having ooth feet on the ped
als, and working them alternately
with scrupulous regularity. Speed
is obtained by aim ply accelerating
this movement. After an hour or
two's practice, tb tyro will be able
lo accomplish a distance of 30 to 40
yards without running the risk of an
upset. Should tho machine incline
on one side, all that? is necessary to
le done is to remove) the foot on the
same side from tho pedal, nnd place
it on the ground. This can, of
course, only lo acoont plished when
the velocipede is of moderate height,
which, by the way, is tho proper kind
of machine for Itcgiunev to make
their first essayn wilh. To alight,
both feet are raised from the pedals
at the same instant, which has the
effect of slackening tlte spaed of the
machine the feet are Ut&n placed
simultaneously on the ground, with
out the handle being let gY. j
a
is
in
PARISIAN USE OF VELOCIPEDES.
Velocipede races; are getting to lie
fashionable in Paris, and are patron
ized by a much better class of pectJ?
than is usually found congregated at
race course The othciata turn
out t masse.
The accounts are graphically de
scribed in Pari papers, from which
me joiiowing leatures or the races
are compiled:
The racing ground is all marked
out with fl-i, twit? there s certain
be a large duster of banners Hying
rom the staj ting place, near to which
scores of tho jockies of these iron
horses are e xercising their docile
steeds. There is no coursing as
with horses. The moment of starti
ng arrives, and the competitors are
drawn up abreast with as great a
distance Ivctween each as the width
the course will allow. At the
'rounding ot the starters flag, legs
work up and down with" a surprising
amount of energy, like the piston of
steam engine.
At these rttces the average length
the course is 1.S00 metres nearly
mile and an eight. At Knghem
this distance was traversed (a por
of it being over a stone-paved
road) in four m mules and tweniy-five
seconds by a velocipede with two
wheels. At Vincennes, the same
distance took Jive minutes forty-five
seconds respectively to ace-otnp'ish,
two whc-l veil 'cipedes only com
peting. Greater speed was attained
St. Cloud, wl re the course of a
mile and a halt, with an int lino of
three in a hiiudrctj for a third of Ihc
distance, was traversed in four min
utes anel lifly seed nds whereas the
final race at Vincei-urs, over a level
course of nearly two mil!s, took
niue minutes ami le n seconds to ac
complish. bo
on
thc-way
the
to
no
er
or
A FURTHER NOVELTY.
A further novelty .is ollered in the
veloci lede lino iu Ihe shape of u
marine mru-hiiie, called the podus
caphe, or vtUnijH.Je jtutiiu. This
machine ia ion&cd or a couple ol
canoes covered with canvas and
joined together with two iron bars,
between which, is a oadtlle-whcel
in motion by means of two pedals
placed at the extremity cf lbe arc
These machines -may be :oi.iutIy
seen inaction ore the lak atEnghein,
even on the Seine itseLf opposite
Tuilleries. The inventor i san
guine that tin Be machines will even
tually attain the same rate of speed
the land velocipede already ac
complishes. Quite recently an en
terprising anutietir ollered to wager
$1U,000 trancs that he would cross
cbannel lietween Boulogne and
Folkstone (30 mCea) on a velocipede
marin within the limitof three hours
wind and weather permitting.
The prizes are not given at these
races for speed alone, but arc aLo
accorded to those who occupy the
longest time in traversing a epecified
distance, a far more difficult pro
ceeding than accomplishing a mile
a few minutes, aa, when going at
snail's pace, it is almost impossible
preserve the pioper balance, and
velocipede and riders are usually
both capsized. In a contest of this
the
the
or
up
wo
the
for
the
a
in
of
m
charac,jr at Vincenies, over a course not
of ICO yards in length, out of six
experienced amateurs who started
only two arrived at the winning post.
The prizes given at the foregoing
contests have been usually gold and
silver meuals and sdver cops; now
and then, however, money prizes of
500 francs are awarded. Several
efforts have been made to induce tha
fair sex to compete at these races,
but hitherto w ithout success, although
they are ready enough to engage in
contest with any casual cavalier
whom they may encounter on his ve
locipede in the Hois de Boulogne.
LAST PHASE OF THE MACHINE.
As if to show what may be done
when the human mind is all ablaze
upon one subject, that what is bene
ficial in one part of the world by a
slight alteration may ba made of
equal service in another, another
phase of the velocipede mania is
opened up. It is this: It is stated
that a Dane has changed the rim of
the wheel and has given it the form
ot a skate's iron or runner, so that a
very high rate fspeetl may be ob
tained on the ice. A box behind the
rider's seat enables him to carry a
gooil load with him. This phase of
the velocipede is said to be growing
in favor iu north Europe.
CONCLUSION.
The above are the outlines and
phases of an excitement nay, a ma
nia which is not only agitating this
coimtry, but is sweeping like wild
Cm: over the whole civilized world.
There must be something in this
mailer, or it would not have strug
gled so long foi success to at last
partially attain it. There is no doubt
principle in all this hubbub, and a
great want yet remains to be satisfied
in the world. We have horse and
steam cars, and steam boats, but there
still a vacuum, and horseflesh can
not supply it. There is travel to be
lone where cars do not run, and
where horse-locomotion would be
impossible. Is not the velocipede
just the thing desired t nether
for business or pleasure, whether
from necessity or exercise, does it
not seem to fill that vacant chair
which vain chimeras have attempted
to sit in for ages May it not be a
revolution? And revolutions once
commenced can never go backward.
If the thing is possible, if a veloci
pede, having the powers attributable
to the machines at present in vogue.
within the range cf human inge
nuity, is not this the age of all others
which it could he best tested
This ia the age of invention the era
of mechanics. The protasstona
stand with cap in baud, while the
builders and workers take all the
honor and profit. It is the aga of
iron. If this velocipede is a bubble,
it will soon be pricked, and its emp
tiness shown. If there is the atom
of a principle in it, brains will scheme
and hands will work until it is fully
developed. If it is a success in any
one of its numerous forms, it will be
all whether on land or in theses,
whether with one wheel or six.
Once a success, iU inerila firmly
established, and the velocipede would
H.conie a national institution. The
broad praiiiesor the West are just
the places to afford it ample scope,
and we would see repeated here the
extravagacces that occur in Paris.
Races would be the order of the day,
and we would fairly live out of doors.
And another grand benefit that
would result froi these machines
would be tho out-door exercise it
would give the ladies and children.
The working of their .velocipedes
Wi3SJ.ll A cidtigatA th ninaoliMJ
expand the chest that consumption
aud dyspepsia would, in a few years,
hardly lijuown among as. A
journey of tea or twenty miles or so
a velocipede .wostld lie a tnfle,
even in the most iccvole and out of-
districts, and would cost only
effort of mounting the tUva ateed.
And then no hostler to feed it, ao
groom to rub it elown, no harness to
bold it, no halter to try it, no halter
Ue it, no stable to shelter it, no
noises to frighten it, no spavin, no
losing wind, no shoeing, no limping,
stopping to drink. Its nerves
never wear out. You do not need to
examine its teeth when you buy it
you needn't care who eired it; wheth
its blood be Morgan or plebeian,
both. You needn't ask if it be
gentle, if it will ebv, or whether it
loliows the carriage, or only goes
under the saddle.
It is a dumb thing; but of ioesli
raable set vice. Once brought into
general use?, and the price lor a ve
locipede would range so low that it
would be wilhiu the means or all lo
purchase one. The beggar might
then own bis immortal horse, ami the
ciippled soldier, as he moved swiftly
around, eouid laugh at the way in
which lie was cheating his crutches.
And, perhaps, for the idea has been
thrown out, our soldiers might hnnt
Indians on the plains with the
velocipede Think of it A veloc
ipede regiment making a charge on
Utes and Cheycnnes, and "paling
inell'tcttial lues'' of Balaklava;
a velocipede battery rushing risht
to the breach which itself had
made, and using 400 uund guns as
now U3e pistols Well, time will
tell,</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82015104/1895-11-16/ed-1/?sp=1&q=motorcycle+motorcycles+vehicle+street+race&r=0.523,0.907,0.452,0.27,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1903-09-08/ed-1/?sp=4&q=motorcycle+motorcycles+vehicle+street+race</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>NEW MOTOR FEDERATION.
American Motorcyclists Organized— To De
sert the Wheelmen's League.
For the purpose of protecting the rights of motor
cyclists and obtaining leirialatlon that will giT*
them more rights, tha Ftderation of American
Motorcyclists was organized la?t night at the
headquarters of the Alpha Motorcycle Club, of
Brooklyn. No. 33 Grant The movement
was started by that organisation and the New-
York Motorcycle Club. Two hundred delegates,
representing various parts of the country, were
present. Tha following officer!* were chosen: R. O
Beits, of New-York, president; N. J. Perry, of
New-Haven, vice-president fir th« Department of
the East; W. Austin, of Daytons. Fla., vice-presi
dent for the Department of the Bouth; L. J. Bird.
of Minneapolis, vice-president for the Department
of the West; W. O. Campbell, of San Francisco,
vice-president for the Department of th* Pacific:
1.. 3. Ferguson, of New-York, secretary, and Dr. C
J. Nlpe. of \Ve«ti>oro. \laas-. treasurer.
The organization of this federation means that
motorcyclists m the future will cot sway from tha
league of American Wheelmen. which, they say.
has not shown enough seal In their t-eb.ilf. Th*
first Kent will be made la New- fork and N«w-J. r-
Sf> where the conflicting laws and regulations re
garding motorcycle* cause th«lr devotee* much an
noyance. Many of ths f*rrtea and railroad* will
not carry motorcycles, although automobile* ar*
received on a'most all feme- now.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1903-11-02/ed-1/?sp=9&q=motorcycle+motorcycles+vehicle+street+race</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>R. G. Bctts's Sen-ices to Motor
cycling The Kennel Shore.
One of the most active workers among motor
cyclist* is R. G. Betts. the arastdaßl of the Feder
ation of American Motorcyclists. Mr. Betfs was
recently elected to this office. The purpose of the
organization is to "encourage the use of motor
cycles and to promote th* reneral Interests of
motorcycling; to ascertain, defer.d and protect the
rights of motorcyclists; to facilitate tour.- to
assist In th* pood roads movement and to advise
and assist in the regulation of motorcycle racing
end other competitions In which motorcycles en
gage." He became Interested In motorcycles while
living In Boston in 1900. his first experter.ee being
R. O. BETTS.
President of the Federation of American Motor
cyclists.
paired on a rented tricycle. In August cf that
V'..ir he sought to creir.iz" the Brst American
motorcycle club, and isM.er! a call ti.it brought
together MM fourteen riders. The meeti! ran
away from its stated purpose, ar.,i. against Mr.
Betts protest, resolved Itself into a '•national"
organisation, Btyled the A?soeiited American Mo
torcyclists. Mr. Betts is a native of Sew-Orleans
and has been connected with bicycle journals for
many rears. Be is now th<- editor of the motor
and bicycle publications publish i by the
rr,:i:-. my. He Id a member of the New-
Tort Mot. Club and the Alpha Motorcycle
Club, and was c: of the foui len I the Uetropole
SS y J v^ C! H« ;s; s also a delegate of the Asso
ciated Cycling Clubs,
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1904-07-20/ed-1/?sp=5&q=motorcycle+motorcycles+vehicle+street+race</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Throueh certain motorcycle riders and andrlralers andrlmlerll an4rlralers
rlralers it in reported that New York or at atIfast litIMllt atleast
least Manhattan borough Is to have a amotorcycle atnotorcycfI atnotnrcyele
motorcycle police squad Inspector Smith Smithit
it Is said lId has become a I convert to the Idea Ideaever Idoapr Ideaever
ever pr since the general adoption about a ayoarngo aflrago aycarago
yoarngo of the grip control which which enables enablesa
a rider to start and step and regulate his hisi hisBPped
p i P speed on one or the e power cycles with one onenand
I hand and without removing it from the theHlecrlng theIeering thesteedng
Hlecrlng bar barA barA barA
A number of members of the New York YorkMotorcycle YorkIMotorcYCle
IMotorcYCle Motorcycle Club and several dealer have haveIeen havePen
len Pen Interviewed by the Inspector with a aview
view Iew to selecting tho best make of machine machineon machineRnd machineand
and several varieties have been tried out outon outtl
on tl the th road by b officers Two patrolmen patrolmenv
v are nr now covering posts on motorcycles motorcyclesratrolman
1 6 1 ratrolman Ennls on Riverside Drive being beingone beingline beingof
one of them themAccording themi themAccording
i According Cordlng to Inspector Smith the only
thing that stands in the way of an Irame Irameiltate ImmellalLate 1mmclit
iltate llalLate clit formation of a motorcycle squad Is Islack IIok
lack ok of funds He considers the machine machinenecessary miohlneanocMaSry machinesnesaary
necessary for chasing c automobiles and run runi rullaal runsways
sways Q4 a4be he hope to be able to get U1e U1emon tkiI
sum money for r rtb tbttabet th Iier tor or i loac loajj</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1905-10-11/ed-1/?sp=7&q=motorcycle+motorcycles+vehicle+street+race</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>POLICE ON MOTORCYCLES WILL
CHASE SPEED MAD AUTOISTS
The imperative demand of the legis
lative committee of the city council to
know why the speed ordinances regu
lating automobiles is not enforced has
been productive of results and the
city council has been requested by the
police commission to purchase two
motorcycles for the benefit of the police
department.
When these motorcycles are secured
and put In commission, woe betide the
motorist who drives his machine faster
than Is reasonable and proper for pub
lic safety. Commissioner Gates Intro
duced the recommendation before the
board yesterday that the council be
Instructed to purchase two of the best
motorcycles that money can buy and
have them equipped with the nsst In
struments for determining: speed.
"Two motorcycles! Two shotguns Is
what we need," was the Indignant ex
plosion of Commissioner James.
Whether Mr. James favored the swift
execution of the speed mad motorist
or would have the Bhotguns used to
puncture the tires was a question of
which he left the commission In doubt.
It was agreed by the commission that
two motorcycles were not enough, but
that it would do for an experiment
and If the results proved satisfactory
more would be ordered.
"We formerly arrested and sometimes
secured convictions of those who ex
ceeded the speed limit, but that wan
when we had an automobile that was
furnished by the Southern California
Automobile association to be used for
that purpose. That automobile hns
been taken away from us and sinca
then we have not been able to catch
the violators of the law.
"With two motorcycles we can keep
up with an automobile, however fust
it is being run, and if we cannot then
arrest the violators we can at least
see the number of the machines and
perhaps identify those who are in It
and have warrants issued for them.
But without the motorcycles we are
powerl3Sß to do anything."
It was the opinion of the mayor that
the speed ordinance should be entirely
abolished and the question of whether
or not motor vehicles were being run
too fast left to the discretion of the
officers to make arrests, whenever they
believed such action was Justified.
It was pointed out, however, by Com
missioners James and Gates, both of
whom are practicing attorney*!, thut
under such a condition there would be
no evidence to present to the courts
iind secure a conviction. Section four
of the speed ordinance provides that
at no time shall a motor vehicle be
run faster than Is reasonable and
proper with regard to public safety.
The maximum limit at which automo
biles may be run in the business Jin
trlct Is twelve mile 3an hour and no
more than four miles an hour while
crossing street Intersections.
"The entire solution of the problem
Is to have a law paßsed by the United
Plates government, making It a crime
to construct automobiles which are
capable of a speed greater than ten or
twelve miles an hour," said Mayor
McAleer, "and the indications are thnt
such a law will soon be passed. The
manufacturers of motor vehicles
thrughout the country recognise that
such a law is lnpvltable and are now
working on models of this type of
machine to be ready for the mnrkfrt
with slow machines when the lav/ Is
passed."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1908-09-09/ed-1/?sp=7&q=motorcycle+motorcycles+vehicle+street+race</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1910-07-31/ed-1/?sp=50&q=motorcycle+motorcycles+vehicle+street+race</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn98047754/1911-09-01/ed-1/?sp=15&q=motorcycle+motorcycles+vehicle+street+race</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>The Motorcycle on the Farm.
If one is to believe tbe statements
of tbe leading motorcycle maufac
turers of the day and their statements
seem logical, it is cheaper to make a
trip to town on a motorcycle than to
drive or walk. A manufacture of one
of these motorcycles (his particular
make holds the world's record for
economy) states thnt while the ma
chine that made the world's record
traveling fifty miles at a cost of less
than one-tenth cent per mile over
country road 9 was operated by an ex
pert, it is nothing unusual for this
particular make of motorcycle in the
bands of an amateur to travel from
six to eight miles on one cent's worth
of gasoline.
Id comparison with the private rid
ing horse the expense per mile is
naturally much less and if one figures
that while the driving horse must be
fed daily, the motorcycle only con
sumes while in use, the difference is
still greater. The limit of a horse for
continuous daily driving is probably
thirty miles, while that of a motor
cycle is over two hundred. Good
traveling for a road horse means ten
miles an hour; good traveling for
a motorcycle from thirty to fifty
miles per hour.
In this age of scaroe hired help,
time, at some season is extremely
valuable to the farmer. His ability
to oover the distance to town and
back with a motorcycle in one fifth of
the road driving horse time and with
no time wasted harnessing and un
harnessing, is a factor to be consider
ed.
Most all tbe good motorcycles are
now equipped with tandem attach
ments and luggage carriers, if desired.
By means of this tandem attachment
two can ride as well as one. The
luggage carrier permits tbe carrying
of small freight, not exoeeding 200
pounds.
Many a farmer, as well as his child
ren, have rebelled at their inability
to go to town, to the swimming hole
or the fishing grounds in the late
summer evening, for a horse cannot
be worked all day and be driven on
the road at night. To these the
motorcycle fills a long felt want. It
is ever ready, costs nothing when idle
and will last for years.
It is really more expensive to be
without a motorcycle than to own
one, just as it is more expensive to
plow with a hand plow, cradle the
grain and use the flail instead of the
modern appliances. The best makes
of motorcycle today can be had for
from $225 up. A motorcycle like
many other pieces of machinery, can
be built too cheaply to be good.
There are, however, several well
established makes, which have years
of successful manufacture behind
them and one will not go amiss in
choosing any of these.
The motorcycle of today has come
to stay. Already in the cities it is
being adopted extensitvely by busi
ness firms because of the great time
saving its use assures.
Repair men, inspection men, etc,
can accomplish triple the work pos
sible with their former horse and
carriage. The saving of time as well
as the great pleasure to be derived
from its use has given the motorcycle
a lasting place in the home c f the
American farmer.
Why Farmers Are Buying 11
I Harley-Daviagoiy I
IB ft/i fit cj h "V f* i_ F" Mm\ IH
J 1 BECAUSE THEY SAVE VALUABLE TIME, 1 1
A With this machine they can go to town in one-fifth the M\\ jg
B 11 M% time consumed driving and a farmers time is worth M\\\ 111
II ji\ mO"ey THEY ARE ECONOMICAL. MMI I
M mi' This machine will travel 10 miles for a cent, m\\\\ m
M^ 5n fnm, never tires, is always ready and cost noth- A mL Ay
jjr anteed by the largest exclusive y^ I |g*' IT'^
*^E Jjr motorcycle factory in the world. I
1 Jn i\''W The Parley-Davidson stock machine if
I W holds the world's economy record and has won yu\\ \M m
■I 11 Jr more races, hill climbs and endurance contests THy
i I |y^ than any other motorcycle made. m 3
j \\W The first Harley-Davidsons we made 10 years I
1 \M ago are still running and giving satisfaction, although W if
they have probably covered 100,000 miles. I
Let us tell you more about this "Silent Gray Fellow." ■II I
H We have just completed an illustrated booklet, en-
titled "The Harley-Davidson on the farm." It's worth 1 I
I reading. Send for your free copy to-day. 6 1
3 HARLEY-DAVIDSON MOTOR CO. II
jII 906 L STREET. MILWAUKEE, WIS. 11</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1915-02-07/ed-1/?sp=24&q=motorcycle+motorcycles+vehicle+street+race</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Preacher. Doctor, Policeman and
J! Soldier Now Use TwoWheeled
Vehicles.
<1
Hundreds of daily demonstrations are
fcroof of the utility, speed and economy j
Of the modern motor cycie. meic >e i
earcely a field of activity that the two- J
wheeler has not entered and proved its
^falue. i
The motor cycle carries the minister)
to reach his patient in less time than ever
before, making: it possible to eliminate
many hours of human suffering.
The motor cycie carried the minister
of th^ gospel on his missions of mercy.
The motor cycle is a part of every progressive
police department, carrying
mounted officers to the scene of crime or
accident, and enabling them to run down
Violators of the law.
The motor cycle aids the forest ranger
ifi protecting our great timber lands from
'lire.
The motor cycle carries mail and delivers
telegrams.
The motor cycle rushes the important
prescription to the bedside of the suf^tVring.
The motor cycle hurries the pulmotor
tj. the beach, where every second counts,
(he effort to restore life.
motor cycle mounted guard accompanies
the I'resident of the United States
his trir.s about the capital.
Motor Cycle in War.
ses of the motor cycie in the army are
almost unlimited. Motor cycle dispat-Ti
riders and scouts have won great fame
Car themselves in the present European
'^iruggle. Machine guns mounted on
motor cycles are carried to their positions
the battlefield motor cycles with sidecars
hurry vsupplies to the lted Cross
workers who are seeking to relieve the i
figured soldiers to the hospitals.
"The motor cycle has revolutionized sig- I
naling on the battlefield," says Henry j
Beach Needham, a war correspondent.
"It has practically done away with wigwagging
on the field. It is economical,
efficient and speedy, and is everywhere
and nowhere as much as at the front."
lTor pleasure, too, the motor cycle has
made a definite place for itself. The ease
with which the two-wheeler is operated,
iis reliability and comfort, make it ail
ideal vehicle for touring. Club sociability
awl endurance runs are enjoyed by thou
oumis of riders all over the couutrv everv
Year.
And more and more we hear of the
ir.nff./ii?t.Jnc. tourist rldinc from ocean i
to ocean, l'rom gulf to lake, around the j
Limited States or circling the globe?tor j
pleasure. Many of those long-distance j
tourists art women, who find as ranch j
Pi casure in the sport as do the men.
MOTOR CYCLE NOTES.
111
The Capital City Motor Cycle Club
of Sacramento, Cal., is making an effort
to secure the 100-mile national
championship for its annual spring
meet.
It has been decided that the next
national motor cycle, bicycle and accessories
show will be held in the Coliseum
in Chicago September L'Q-25.
Sanction has just been issued by the
Federation of American Motor Cyclists
i or a iuu-mne moior cycle meei iu uc
held at Calesbuiig, 111., July
The Wheeling" (W. Va.) Motor Cycle
Club is planning: to have a tri-state
reunion of motor cyclists during the
coming- summer.
In planning for the coming season's
events the Worcester (Mass.) Motor
Cycle Club has set Patriots' day, April
10, for the opening run, which will be
to Concord, Lexington and return.
Though less than two months old,
(the motor cycle club of St. Paul, Minn.,
has reached a membership mark of 100.
lit is the purpose of the club to raise
this to 250 by next fall.
A ifew motor cycle dub has been
formed in Cincinnati, Ohio, known as
the Queen City M. C. It has twentytwo
charter members. The organization
is planning to affiliate with the
F. A. M.
A. Y. Letts of Ilohoken, X. J., has
made his motor cycle help him earn
quite a bit of money this winter. He
attached the motor to a skate sharpener,
with which he has kept the
skates of the community in good condition.
Frank Middleton of Atlantic City,
X'. J., whose business is the painting
of show cards anrl large signs, uses a
motor cycle to take him #er the city
in quest of new business.
A retail shoe concern of Chicago has
used a motor cycle in working out a
novel advertising scheme. Mounted on
the two-wheeler is a traveling show
case in which the latest models of
shoes are displayed. The motor cycle i
is also used for firactical delivery purposes.
I
Nearly 200 riders and their friends
participated in the recent annual >>an-
quet of the Rockford fill.) Motor Cycle
Club.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-yellowstone</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id></id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id></id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
